

PROFILE

+2 years' experience with diligence in scripting powerful set of web technology tools and design. I strive for excellence, strong work ethic and professionalism. I seek to deliver solutions that meet customer's demands and high commercial value for an organization.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH: 03 April 1992

GENDER: Male

ID NUMBER: 9204036100344 LANGUAGE: siSwati, English

CONTACT

PHONE:

+27 67 098 0127

ALTENATIVE PHONE:

+27 68 412 5201

PORTFOLIO WEBSITE:

simonkosi.netlify.app

EMAIL

simosakhenkosi@gmail.com

HOBBIES

Learning
Exploring/ Travel
Running/ work-out
Yoga/ Meditation

SIMOSAKHE DLAMINI

Full Stack Web Developer

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, Ruby, JSON (XML, AJAX, and Web APIs), Node.js (Express.js), D3js, Linux, Git and GitHub, Microsoft Suite, User Experience (UX), User Interface (UI) Design, and SEO.

Framework

React and Redux with Gatsby and Material UI

Database

Mongo DB/Mongoose with Node.js and Express

Content Management Systems

WordPress, Shopify

EDUCATION DETAILS

University of Pretoria (UP)

2010 - 2014 [Incomplete]

Bachelor of commerce faculty, major in BCom (Informatics)

Mathews Phosa College

2010 - 2011

Matriculation with a Bachelor's Degree

CERTIFICATIONS

FreeCodeCamp

- Responsive Web Design (HTML, CSS, Flexbox, CSS Grid)
- Front End Libraries (React, Redux, Sass, Bootstrap, ¡Query)
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures (JavaScript)
- Data Visualization (D3.js)
- APIs and Microservices (Node.js, Express.js, databases)
- Information Security and Quality Assurance (Chai, Helmet.js, BCrypt, Passport.js)

Mathews Phosa College

National Senior Certificate – Bachelor's Degree

WORK EXPERIENCE

NKOSI imperial Digital Solutions [The Reeds, Centurion]

February 2020 – Present

Position: Freelancing Web Developer

Duties:

- Interfaced with clients to identify business requirements for business proposals.
- Provided design solutions for my community and clients by creating websites with hosting services, logos, flyers, resumes, invitation cards, and advertisements.
- Utilized Microsoft Suite and Google services to meet clients' demands.
- Obtained more knowledge on new technologies, and trends in web development.
- Worked to meet client deadlines.

Freelance Work [Lyttleton Manor, Centurion]

January 2019 - 2020

Position: Freelancing Web Developer

Duties:

- I created a website for DMH Do My Hair Salon located using Template.
- I designed flyers for DMH Salon, THE LOCAL BAR, and product designs for EDEN CHOICE oats, soya milk, Himalayan salt and granola.
- I utilized Web APIs to create RESTful web applications.
- Applied content managements systems with WordPress and WooCommerce for a commercial website
- Managed Databases for database-based web applications.
- I created fun command line interface (CLI) board games with Ruby.

Casa Bella [Loftus Park – Woodlands]

May 2018 – October 2020 Position: Front Ambassador

Duties:

- Utilized Pilot restaurant software for sales, inventory and purchases.
- Demonstrated genuine hospitality while greeting and establishing rapport with guests.
- Maintained high standards of cleanliness and sanitation.
- Upheld highest standard for cleanliness of glass and silverware.
- Described menu items, special offerings, and appropriately identified wine pairings.

KOI [Lynnwood Bridge – Menlyn Maine]

September 2015 – April 2018

Position: Front Waiter

Duties:

- Utilized Pilot restaurant software for sales, inventory and purchases.
- Demonstrated genuine hospitality while greeting and establishing rapport with guests.
- Maintained high standards of cleanliness and sanitation.
- Upheld highest standard for cleanliness of glass and silverware.
- Described menu items, special offerings, and appropriately identified wine pairings.

News Cafe [Menlyn Park]

December 2014 – August 2015 Position: Front Bartender

Duties:

- Utilized Micros restaurant software for sales, inventory and purchases.
- Handled +-R 20 000 cash on a daily basis, which built trustworthiness and loyalty with owners.
- Checked identification to enforce age requirement for alcoholic beverages.
- Ensured superior service and efficiency at all times.
- Closed out cash register with 99% accuracy and prepared cashier report.
- Managed bar inventory, restocked supplies, and placed orders for spirits, beer, wines, and mixers.
- Up sold daily specials and beverage promotions to exceed daily sales goals.